Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Norman H. Strouse Papers, 1852-1990 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Personal Materials Series, 1852-1990 and undated, 6 Boxes
  - Memorabilia, 1934-1986
    - Norman H. Strouse: A Collection of Rememberences on the Occasion of His Retirement from the Chairmanship of the J. Walter Thompson Company, edited by Arnold Grisman and Colin C. Dawkins, 1969 (Box 28)
    - Norm Strouse: This Is Your Life in Posters, booklet, undated (Box 28)
    - Original small ad that started Norman Strouse in advertising business, 1925 (Box 28)
    - Pease scrapbook materials, 1934-1968 (Box 28)
      [Includes signed letter from President Dwight Eisenhower regarding accomodations during the dedication of the AMerican Red Cross Chapter Building in 1963. Also includes transcript of Strouse's 1963 Profit speech.]
    - Poem to First Lady of JWT, Charlotte Strouse, 1955 (Box 29)
    - Salvation Army centenary paperweight, 1965 (Box 29)
    - Strouse 80th birthday resolution, JWT board of directors, 1986 (Box 29)
    - Strouse memorabilia inventory, 1964 (Box 29)
  - Photographs
    - Luchesi Portrait, 1969, (5 folders) (Box 29)
      [Includes photographs, negatives and related newsletters.]
    - Strouse family and friends, ca. 1910-1955, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - Vacation in Germany,1960s (Box 29)
- Oversize Materials, 10 Boxes
  Contains oversize materials removed from previous series.
  - General JWT office files
    - Clippings and photographs
      - Scrapbook, 1956-1960 (Box OV1)
      - Clippings, general (Box OV2)
        - 1955, 1962 (Box OV2)
        - 1852, 1947-1967 (Box OV2)
      - Detroit office, 1953, 1967-1968
        - (Includes contents of a scrapbook documenting Norman Strouse's election as vice president, as well as photos and sketches of wartime Manila, 1939-1946.) (Box OV2)
      - Chicago Tribune JWT special, 1964 (Box OV2)
      - Detroit Times special, 1955 (Box OV2)
      - Times (London) supplement on JWT, 1962 (Box OV2)
      - Wall Street Journal advertisement featuring Norman Strouse, ca. 1970s (Box OV2)
    - Company History
      - Adman Who Makes a Difference, Business Week, photographs and article, 1966 (Box OV2)
    - Corporate Administration, 1955-1959
      - Contents of an album to commemorate Dan Seymour, undated (Box OV2)
      - General organization, 1955 (Box OV2)
      - Detroit office
        - Scrapbook covering Strouse's election to JWT Vice-President, including photographs of wartime Manila, 1945-1947 and undated (Box OV2)
        - In-house spoof of billboard advertisement, ca. 1950 (Box OV2)
        - Strouse-client relationships chart, 1979 (Box OV2)
      - Puerto Rico trip, 1963 (Box OV2)
      - San Francisco office
        - Framed letter from Stanley Resor to Norman Strouse at the San Francisco office, 1936 (Box OV2)
    - Corporate administration, general correspondence files, 1955-1967 (Box OV2)
  - Professional associations
    - General correspondence, 1956-1964 (Box OV2)
  - Business writings and speeches
    - Folder including background articles related to 1961 speeches, 1961 (Box OV2)
  - Detroit office
    - Ford Motor Company, Baby Talk billboard scrapbook, ca. 1947 (Box OV3)
  - Personal Materials (Box OV4)
    - Memorabilia
      - Belgische Impressionen, color sketches of Belgium produced by JWT Frankfurt, 1963 (Box OV4)
      - Bound copy of Strouse's honorary doctorate diploma from the University of California, 1967 (Box OV4)
      - Cartoon to celebrate the 100th birthday of JWT featuring Strouse and George Reeves, ca. 1964 (Box OV4)
      - Cartoon featuring Norman Strouse and golf, undated (Box OV4)
      - Certificate of achievement from London office, 1962 (Box OV4)
      - Christmas greetings, Sunset and JWT celebrate 60 years, undated (Box OV4)
      - Citation to Norman Strouse on the occassion of his winning the Franklin Award at the Printing Week dinner, 1965 (Box OV4)
      - Matted Time cover, 1962 (Box OV4)
      - Resolution by the JWT Board and advertisement commemorating Strouse's 80th birthday, 1986 (Box OV4)
    - Photographs
      - Portrait of Strouse in uniform, ca. 1940s (Box OV4)
      - Portrait photographs with inscriptions to Strouse, undated
        - (Photographs include Bill Laurie, Kenn Hinks, Wally Elton, Dan Seymour, George Reeves and Ed Wilson.) (Box OV4)
      - Portrait photograph of Ted Jardine with personal dedication to Strouse, undated (Box OV4)
    - Scrapbook (Box OV5)
      - Photographic recording of Strouse's visit to Japan, 1964 (Box OV5)
      - Silver bowl, ca. 1959 (Box OV6)
        [Presented to Strouse by Helen and Stanley Resor to commemorate Strouse's 30 years of service at JWT. Presentation also marked Resor's retirement as CEO of JWT and Strouse's appointment to that position. Bowl is an exact copy of one made by Paul Revere in 1768.]
      - Photo album documenting Luchesi sculpture (Includes captions written by Luchesi.), 1968 (Box OV7)
      - Tribute to the Advertising Industry commemorative plaque, accepted by Norman Strouse, AAAA Chairman, 1964 (Box OV8)
      - Strouse 70th birthday greetings, bound in velvet box, 1966 (Box OV9)
      - Norman H. Strouse: A Collection of Rememberences on the Occasion of His Retirement from the Chairmanship of the J. Walter Thompson Company, edited by Arnold Grisman and Colin C. Dawkins, 1969 (Box OV10)